[Music]
Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and
today we've got one more
episode in our series
about interview skills.
This is an elementary
level series and we're
here today to talk about
things that you might
not be very good at.
That's right today we're
going to talk about
weaknesses and that is our
word for vocabulary preview.
So let's take a look at it now.
Vocabulary preview. Okay
so what is a weakness?
A weakness is a thing or
an activity or something
that you're just not very
good at or something
that you think you can
improve. Okay so obviously
no one is perfect
and like we saw in the
previous lesson we had
a lot of good things about
ourselves key strengths
and now we're going to
talk about our weaknesses
maybe you're a little bit
lazy that might be a
weakness. That's right so
weakness is the opposite
of strength and that is
the topic today so let's take
a listen to today's dialogue.
Okay Rebecca well I think you've given me a
clear impression of your positive qualities
but let's talk a little bit
about your weaknesses.
Okay well it's always
more difficult to
describe them isn't
it? Definitely but if you
had to pinpoint one
weakness what would it be?
Well as I mentioned
before I do tend to get
frustrated if I don't see
progress in my work or career.
I suppose I'm quite
a restless character.
My father always taught
me to be a high achiever.
So would you say if things don't go your
way at work it could easily get you down?
Well in a way yes but
I must say that even if
I'm not completely happy
in my work I always give
110% I would never
shirk my responsibilities.
I suppose sometimes I
expect too much too soon.
Well you know journalism
is a highly competitive
world so you do need to
keep pushing yourself it's true.
Okay well let's move on to talk about
the job position here shall we? Yes please.
All right we're back so
obviously Rebecca did a
very good job at talking
about her weaknesses in a
very positive way. So
before we get into analyzing
that why don't we take
a look at a couple of
words used on language
takeaway? Language takeaway.
One of the first words that Mr.
Parsons used was a clear
impression so impression.
All right so I think this is a
very common word when people
talk about first impressions
or I get the impression
so what is an impression?
Well an impression
is like an idea or a
feeling so I can have an
impression about something
it means that I don't
necessarily understand
it really well or I don't
have experience with
it but it's it's an idea
that I have about
something. That's right so
for example maybe you
meet somebody new and you
say I get the impression
that he is liar but
maybe then you get to
know him and he's not so
this is your this is your
idea about something or
the way you feel about
something so in this case
Mr. Parsons has a clear
impression of her positive
qualities that means
that he has an idea or an
understanding of the
things that Rebecca is good
at but he wants to know
more about her weaknesses.
That's right and
Mr. Parsons asked her to try
and pinpoint one of
her weaknesses so this
word to pinpoint. This
is a great word I'm not
really sure where it
comes from in English but I
think it's very visual you
can see what the word means.
A pinpoint means to to locate or identify
or really be specific about something.
That's right so maybe if you
go to the doctor and you say
that your back hurts the
doctor might ask you to
try and pinpoint where on
your back you have the pain.
That's right so it's
a way to be specific
or very exact about
something. Okay so if she
had to pinpoint something
she said well I do get a
little bit frustrated. Okay so
frustrated is a way you feel.
I feel frustrated.
He is frustrated.
It's uh it's basically
a feeling that you get
when you have to do
something but you don't
think you can do it or
maybe something annoys you
and you get frustrated.
For example when people
tap like this and I'm
working I get frustrated
because it's a distraction.
Okay so everyone
has different things
that frustrate them.
Now if we take a look at
this word uh it is actually an
adjective and we usually
use it you get frustrated
or as you said
you feel frustrated.
So remember it may look
like a verb but it's actually an
adjective that ends an ED
frustrated to get frustrated.
He got frustrated or
we feel very frustrated.
Okay and well apart
from being frustrated she
also said that she is
a restless character.
Okay so someone is restless if they don't
like to stay in one place all the time.
That means someone who wants
to move around or to go places
or to travel or to see
new things is restless.
That's right so she has
a restless character that
means she likes to move
around. She doesn't like
to stand still in one place.
Maybe she gets bored very easily.
Okay so that's
somebody that would
be restless but moving
on she also said that
she doesn't like to
shirk her responsibilities.
Okay you often hear
these words go together so
responsibilities are
things that we need to do.
Things that other
people expect us to do.
To shirk a responsibility
means to not do something that
you're supposed to do. It means to
avoid responsibility or to push it away.
Okay so it's a verb but to
shirk your responsibilities.
You shouldn't shirk
your responsibilities.
That's right. All right
so a lot of interesting
key words there why don't
we listen to the dialogue
again and we'll be back
with Fluency Builder.
Okay Rebecca well I think
you've given me a clear
impression of your
positive qualities but let's
talk a little bit about
your weaknesses. Okay
well it's always more difficult to describe
them isn't it? Definitely but if you had to
pinpoint one weakness
what would it be?
Well as I mentioned before
I do tend to get frustrated
if I don't see progress
in my work or career.
I suppose I'm quite
a restless character.
My father always taught
me to be a high achiever
so. So would you say if
things don't go your way
at work it could
easily get you down?
Well in a way yes but I
must say that even if I'm not
completely happy in my
work I always give 110% I
would never shirk
my responsibilities.
I suppose sometimes I
expect too much too soon.
Well you know journalism is
a highly competitive world so
you do need to keep
pushing yourself it's true.
Okay well let's move
on to talk about the job
position here shall we?
Yes please. So we've picked
out three key phrases
for you on Fluency Builder
let's take a look at
those now. Starting with
Mr. Parsons saying so
would you say if things don't
go your way at work it
could easily get you down?
Two great phrases there.
That's right so the first
phrase if things don't go
your way. So this is kind
of a funny phrase when
you think about it because
they go your way like
to me or what is my way.
This basically means if
things do not happen in a way
that makes you happy or
in a way that you expect.
Okay so we could say
he lost his job he couldn't
pay his bills things
just didn't go his way.
That's right so things are
not happening as he planned
or as he expected. You
can also say the opposite
so he won the lottery
and he also met a really
beautiful girl who
wanted to be his girlfriend
things were going his
way. Okay very good so if
things are going your
way it's good if things
aren't going your way
then it's bad. That's right.
Okay and so if things
aren't going Rebecca's way
does that mean that it
could easily get her down?
Okay so to get you down
or to get someone down
means to make you sad
upset or frustrated like
that where we just
heard. So you could ask
someone like Marco what
gets you down? rainy days.
That's a good one. Yeah
rainy days get me down too.
So it's kind of a way of saying what makes
you sad or depressed or what makes you
unhappy or in this case if
something doesn't happen
as you planned it if
it doesn't go your way
does that make you sad?
Does that get you down?
Okay very good so a very
good question there and
she responded that kind
of yeah that does happen
but she always tries
to give 110 percent.
Okay so this is a really
funny phrase because you
think I can give
everything I have I can work
really hard and that's
100 percent but we say 110
percent means you
do more than you can.
It's like pushing yourself
more than it's possible.
That's right so this is a
very common phrase in
sports and business people
are saying for example
I always remember my
coach saying I want you
guys to give me 110
percent out there that means
like I really want you
to try very hard to do
as much as possible.
Even more than your best
more than you think you
can do. Exactly so again
it refers to the effort that
you put into something
it can be in business
sports anything.
And she's basically saying I
always do more than my best.
I do as much as
humanly possible.
That's right okay so a lot of
great stuff there from Rebecca
why don't we listen to her to her
one last time and we'll be back in a bit.
Okay Rebecca well I
think you've given me
clear impression of
your positive qualities but
let's talk a little bit
about your weaknesses.
Okay well it's always more
difficult to describe them isn't it?
Definitely but if you had to pinpoint
one weakness what would it be?
Well as I mentioned before
I do tend to get frustrated
if I don't see progress
in my work or career.
I suppose I'm quite
a restless character.
My father always taught
me to be a high achiever.
So would you say if things don't go your
way at work it could easily get you down?
Well in a way yes but
I must say that even if
I'm not completely happy
in my work I always give
a hundred and ten percent.
I would never shock my
responsibilities. I suppose
sometimes I expect too much too soon.
Well you know
journalism is a highly
competitive world so you
do need to keep pushing
yourself it's true. Okay
well let's move on to talk
about the job position
here shall we? Yes please.
All right so talking
about weaknesses I think
one of the common mistakes
when people talk about
weaknesses is they say they
work too much and everyone
says you should never
say that in an interview.
Yeah I think it's a it's a
bad way to talk about
yourself because a boss
or an employer really
wants to hear a real
weakness and I work too
hard is a way of saying
I have no weaknesses.
I'm actually really really
perfect. I just think it's
a lazy answer so maybe
you should avoid saying I
work too hard and really
focus on things that you
you do have to to work
on and then I think the key
is to say that I know
this is something that I
have a hard time with. I
know this is a weakness
and I'm trying to improve
it. Yeah I remember in
some of the interviews
I've had I think my common
answer was I'm sometimes
I'm very late I'm not
very punctual so but
you know it's a it's a real
weakness and well it
may seem like difficult but
then you give it a little
spin by saying yeah I'm
sometimes not very
punctual but then I try to
make up for it maybe it's
staying more time at the
office or sometimes I
try to wake up a little bit
earlier and make it on
time I don't know something
like that. Right so the
key there is just to show
that you know it's a problem
that you're trying to work on it.
Yeah so this is actually the hardest
part for me of an interview talking about
yourself in a negative
way because obviously
you want to get the job
so you want to make sure
that the employer has a good
idea of yourself but it's hard.
I think it's the hardest
part for everyone.
Yeah I don't
think it's just you.
Yeah it's hard so this is an
interesting topic why don't
you practice and come
to our website englishpot.
com and on our comments section why
don't you tell us what your weaknesses are.
That's right we hope to hear
from you of course you can also
share with us your
strengths on our lesson about
strengths but in this one
I recommend everyone
practice this because
it will come up at some
point and it's good
to get the practice in so
englishpot.com we hope to see you there.
All right guys bye!